



About Me

My goal is to become associated with a company where I can utilize my skills and gain further experience while enhancing the company's productivity and reputation.

Contact



017 95 62 1796

tusar8145@gmail.com

18/5-A Tallabag Road, Poschim Rajabazar, Near Dhanmondi 27, Dhaka 1207



Education

Program: BSc in CSE 2015-2019

Institute:

University of Asia Pacific

Result: CGPA 3.66 out of 4

Passing Year: 2019
Achievement: 4 Vice
Chancellor Award

HSC Passing Year 2014 From Sirajganj Collectorate College, Sirajganj. GPA 4.20 out of 5

SSC Passing Year 2012 From Panchlia Badrul Alam High School, Sirajganj. GPA 4.31 out of 5

Md. Abdulla Al Mamun

Laravel, Flutter, React Js, Vue Js

expert

Employment History

4.5+ Years of Full Stack Web Development Experience







1. <u>Senior Developer Jan 2022 - Present</u>

Company: US Bangla Group

Job Responsibility: Ecommerce Development using Laravel & App

Development using Flutter.

Corporate Office: Road no-1A, House No-32, Baridhara J Block, Dhaka.

Link: https://shoplover.com

Contact: +8801322-819423 (Shoplover)



2. Senior Software Engineer May 2021 - Dec. 2021

Company: Engineers Consortium Limited

Job Responsibility: Website Management, Tender Management, Project Management and Accounting Software Development

Company Location: 870 Shewrapara, Rokeya Sarani Dhaka 1216, Bangladesh. Link: https://engineersconsortium/td.com.bd
Contact: +880 2 4803 8361, +88017 2777 9444 (ECL)

BONGSHAL

3. Website & Software Developer -2021 Contractual

Company: Bongshal.com

Company Location: 51/1 Bongshal Road, Dhaka-1100, Dhaka Division, Bangladesh.

Link: https://bongshal.com Contact: +88017 60580023

4. Website Developer & IT Support -2020 Contractual

Company: Deshcollection

Company Location: Alpana plaza, New Elephant Road, Dhaka-1205, Bangladesh.

Link: https://deshcollection.com Contact: +88017 64077435 5. Website Developer & IT Support -2019 Contractual

Company: Desh Matrika Food Products Company

Company Location: Bahirgola Road, Sirajganj-600, Bangladesh. Link: https://deshmatrikabd.com Contact: +88019 68870000

6. Website Developer & IT Support -2018 Contractual

Company: Lal Sobuj Foundation Contact: 016 82609763

Company Location: 38/2, Ajij Khan Road, Mohammadpur, Dhaka-1208.

7. <u>Software Developer & IT Support -2019</u> Contractual

Company: Niaz & Brothers

Company Location: Bhasani Road, Sirajganj. Contact: 017 30441144

Expertise Work

1. Full Stack Web Development

• Website & Admin Panel Development

I have completed more than 10 websites using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JS, React js, Core php, OOP, Codelgniter, Laravel. Below are some links:

	Link	Development Year
1	https://shoplover.com	2022
2	https://engineersconsortiumltd.com.bd	2021
3	https://deshmatrikabd.com	2020
4	https://lalsobuj.org.bd	2018
5	https://matsolutionsinc.com	2019
6	https://rainenterprisebd.com	2121

• Ecommerce Development & Customization

I have developed and customize more than 4 ecommerce websites. There are some purchase websites that i have customized according to the client's requirements. Below are some links:

	Link	Development Year	Customize By
1	https://shoplover.com	2022	Laravel
2	https://bongshal.com	2021	Laravel
3	https://bigvaly.com.bd	2020	Codelgniter
4	https://deshcollection.com	2019	WordPress

Accounting & Inventory Software Development

I have developed modern, multifunctional, advanced, Dynamic Accounting & Inventory Management Software Using OOP & Codelgniter. Number of **4** Distributors are using this software. Below are links:

	Link	Period of	Clients
		use	
1	https://supercrete.niazandbrothers.com	1 year	Supercrete Cement Distributor Sirajganj
2	https://fresh.niazandbrothers.com	1 year	Fresh Cement Distributor Sirajganj
3	https://cocacolasj.matsolutionsinc.com	2 years	Coca-Cola Distributor Sirajganj
4	https://maricosj.matsolutionsinc.com	2 years	Marico Distributor Sirajganj

School Management Software Development

I have developed and customize school management software with all essential features. 6 Schools and colleges are using this software. Below are links:



Content Management System: WordPress

I have extensive experience in theme, website and plugin customization in WordPress development,

Expertise Work

2. Software Architecture, Testing, Quality Control

I have extensive experience in simply designing any complicated system, software architecture, database design, testing and quality control to ensure that a software product will meet its quality goals at the best value to the customer. I have used a number of tools for software testing.

3. Mobile Application Development

- Android Application Development using Android Studio [Flutter, Java]

 I have developed several Android applications for google play store. Below are some links:
 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.shoplover
 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.androstock.deshcollection
 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bongshal.com
- IOS Application Development using XCode-IDE-Apple [Flutter]
 I have experience developing iOS software for App Store.

4. Branding, Advertisement, Digital Marketing, Content Writing, SEO

I have extensive experience in Facebook marketing and boosting and experience writing content for several websites. I have also experience in keyword research, On Page SEO, Off Page SEO and making SEO friendly website.

5. Server Manage

I used the following cloud platform and hosting servers to host my website or software:

AWS, DigitalOcean, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Bluehost, Namecheap, HostGator and many more.

I have huge experience on WHM, cPanel, CyberPanel, S3 File System, Redis, Load balancing.

6. Research & Development

My thesis title: Secure Some REST API and Boost Cyber Security by Blockchain for Recommendation System. I have extensive experience in research and development in the following sectors.

Web Security				
Secure TransmissionAuthenticationAuthorization	+++	Cryptography Data Validation Specific Risky Functionality		
Artificial Intelligence & Deep learning				
 Artificial Intelligence & Software Engineering 	+	Al Project Development		
Blockchain				
 Ethereum blockchain and deploy a Solidity Smart Contract on the blockchain 	4	Implement Blockchain in software development		

7. Hardware & Software Combination

- **Bulk SMS sender:** I have developed this device using NodeMCU, GPRS Module which can fetch data from server and perform send SMS.
- **♣ Biometric Web based Attendance Device:** I have developed this device using ESP8266, Fingerprint module, RFID Module, oled display. This device is being used to take the attendance of students in some schools.
- Production Counter: I set a production counter at a flour mill that can count bags.

Expertise Work

8. Game Development

I have little experience in the unity game engine. I created 3D games using unity software.

9. Graphics Design

I have extensive experience in logo design, Cover making, Video Editing, Animation & Tutorials Making. I used to perform this task following tools:

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Premier Pro
- Sony Vegas Pro

- Adobe illustrator
- Adobe After Effect
- Wondershare Filmora
- ♣ Power Director 16

Field of Specialization

- ♣ HTML5 & CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ReactJS, Vue JS, jQuery AJAX
- MySQL database
- ♣ Core php, php 7+8, Python, Codelgniter, Laravel Framework, C++/ VC++, Java, Dart, Solidity

Language Proficiency

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Bangla	High	High	High
English	High	High	Medium

Personal Details

Father's Name	:	Md. Abdul Hakim Akanda
Mother's Name	:	Shirina Ferdusi
Date of Birth	:	August 15, 1995
Gender	:	Male
Marital Status	:	Single
Nationality	:	Bangladeshi
Permanent Address	:	Nalka, Raiganj, Sirajganj
Current Location	:	18/5-A Tallabag Road, Poschim Rajabazar, Near Dhanmondi 27, Dhaka 1207

Reference

Name		Dr. Addul Salam Akanda
Organization	:	BUET
Designation	:	Professor, Dept. of ME
Address	:	BUET
Mobile	:	01934123047
E-Mail	:	masalamakanda@me.buet.ac.bd
Relation	:	Uncle